

# Joseph Gordon

jegordon42@gmail.com in linkedin.com/in/joseph-e-gordon

**Software Engineer** 

(732) 870 - 7797

github.com/jegordon42

## **PROFILE**

Highly passionate web application developer with 4 years of full time and 7 years of part time experience. I am comfortable navigating the full stack and thrive in collaborative environments where I can learn from others, share my knowledge, and make an outstanding impact on end users.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Google August 2022 - Present

Software Engineer, Google Cloud Platform

Austin, TX

- Migrated CRM Salesforce workflow used by 8000+ user support agents to an in-house solution, minimizing dependencies and overhead
- Led development of an app to display a support ticket's activity, allowing users to effectively manage 10,000+ support tickets a week
- Built a UI that queried structured customer data to diagnose the issues of support tickets, saving 1000+ hours a week on closing support tickets
- Independently designed and built a commenting app, facilitating 100,000+ weekly communications between agents and customers
- Pioneered a service used by apps to upload and download file attachments, supporting 1000+ files daily
- Instituted a framework to track user metrics for agent products to find areas for growth, leading to a more agile development process
- Utilized Angular, Java, SQL, JavaScript, HTML

Bank of America July 2020 - June 2022

Software Engineer New York, NY

Worked on a data regression tool to support internal teams that processed millions of data comparisons a day

- Built three applications independently to automate tedious business processes saving users one to three hours a week
- Developed UI automation tests for our team's applications, saving the QA team from having to manually perform a hundred tests every release
- Planned and executed the redesign of the team's main application resulting in improved UX, speeds and data utilization
- Collaborated with PM and end users to plan and implement features for releases
- Utilized React, Python, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, Flask, Jenkins, Jinja, Selenium

Genewiz May 2018 - January 2020

Software Engineering Intern

Software Engineering Intern

- Worked on an ordering platform that managed over a million genetic sequencing requests and results per year
- Organized and led meetings to gather and implement requirements from other business departments
- Led a project to handle Genewiz employees' hours for each week, generating a detailed summary from excels
- Utilized ASP.Net, MVC, C#, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, Visual Studio and SSMS

## Targeted Technologies, L.L.C.

June 2013 - January 2018

South Plainfield, NJ

Toms River, NJ

- Worked on a 3-person team that made custom software for each of the 15 clients to handle their workflows
- Built an ordering platform for a packaging supply business that had over 100,000 products
- Developed an app for a chemical supply business that managed over a million orders and used algorithms to calculate properties of solutions
- Utilized ASP.Net, MVC, C#, VB, VBA, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, Crystal Reports, Visual Studio and SSMS

#### **PROJECTS**

Resume Website January 2024

Personal Project

joseph-gordon.com

A React app to showcase my resume with an AI chatbot to answer questions about me that leverages OpenAI

**JoeLinks** October 2023

Personal Project

joelinks.net

A web app to create Short URLs with a React frontend and firebase for storage and authentication

BluBudget March 2021 - February 2022

Personal Project

A Web(React) and IOS(React Native) app to keep track of one's budget as well as create data science visuals to show transaction trends. Used Flask app for backend logic, a SQL DB for data storage and Firebase for authentication.

### **SKILLS**

Programming: Java, JavaScript, Python, C, C#, VB, VBA, SQL, Swift, HTML/CSS

Frameworks / Databases: React, React Native, Angular, .Net, MVC, Flask, Selenium, SQL

DevOps / Cloud Services: Jenkins, Azure DevOps, Azure Database and Application Hosting, AWS S3, Firebase

## **EDUCATION**